<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nikola Stoyanov</title>
    <link>https://niksto.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Nikola Stoyanov</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://niksto.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://niksto.net/portfolio/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://niksto.net/portfolio/research/</guid>
      <description> Cohesive models for crack opening using the PPR model. Structural behaviour of cracks in fire. Protection materials for low and high temperatures. Canny edge detection for SEM micrographs. Post-processing for the contour method package pyCM. Inverse heat transfer modeling.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://niksto.net/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://niksto.net/about/</guid>
      <description>About Hello! My name is Nikola Stoyanov and I am a PhD student at the University of Manchester in the Mechanical, Aerospace and Civil Engineering department. I also did my MEng degree in Civil Engineering - again in Manchester.
  My research interests are the structural and material performance of low carbon steel when exposed to cryogenic temperatures (more specifically Liquefied Natural Gas) and followed by hydrocarbon fire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sketching for Outeach</title>
      <link>https://niksto.net/posts/cool_sketching/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://niksto.net/posts/cool_sketching/</guid>
      <description>Sketching   
Creating sketches/drawings for an outreach event targeted at non-technical audience is time consuming and it would be best to reuse what we already have. In my case all of my figures are generated using PGF/TikZ and are great quality, however, I would not consider them suitable for some audiences. In this post I am showing the use of Rough.js to convert my figures to sketches targeted for school outreach events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Fractals</title>
      <link>https://niksto.net/posts/exploring_fractals/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://niksto.net/posts/exploring_fractals/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I recently rewatched a video from Arthur C. Clarke which is where I first saw what fractals are. I saw this video while I was in high school and having rewatched it now I wondered if I can generate the Mandelbrot set and explore some parts of it myself. I did a quick search online and I discovered that Jean Francois Puget had already done that and achieved great results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python and VTK scientific visualisation</title>
      <link>https://niksto.net/posts/crackvis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://niksto.net/posts/crackvis/</guid>
      <description>Background CrackVis is a visualisation tool which uses VTK to display a point cloud from ABAQUS 2D simulations. The input is a csv file which holds data in the following format:
   X Y Z1 Z2 &amp;hellip;     &amp;hellip; &amp;hellip; &amp;hellip; &amp;hellip; &amp;hellip;    Where \(X\) and \(Y\) are the coordinates of the nodes and \(Z_n\) is the data to be investigated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs Configuration File</title>
      <link>https://niksto.net/posts/emacs_config/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://niksto.net/posts/emacs_config/</guid>
      <description>Emacs Configuration Here is the compulsory screenshot of my Emacs setup and this page being edited.
  Below I have presented the main parts of my configuration which might be of interest.
Initialize Load melpa and custom packages. Here I also load ox-rss which is later used to generate the rss feed for this blog.
(package-initialize) ;; load emacs 24&#39;s package system. Add MELPA repository. (when (&amp;gt;= emacs-major-version 24) (require &#39;package) (add-to-list &#39;package-archives &#39;(&amp;quot;melpa&amp;quot; .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Blog Post</title>
      <link>https://niksto.net/posts/first_post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://niksto.net/posts/first_post/</guid>
      <description>Hi I have just finished building this blog from Emacs and Org Mode. My intention is to blog about my work during my PhD and since I do almost all of my report writing work in Org Mode I needed a system with which I can upload content quickly and easily.
The website is built using the script detailed in the blog of Dennis Ogbe using nothing else but the built-in functionality of Org Mode and some elisp.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>